Louis Young

Full-stack Software Engineer [Web | Mobile]

Rue du Maupas 33, Lausanne, Switzerland louis.young0420@gmail.com +41 22 548 01 93

A full-stack software engineer with 7 years of experience embracing a wide range of **JavaScript** technologies and creative **UI/UX** sense. I am a senior front-end engineer who has specialized in **React** and **Vue.js**, as well as other popular JavaScript frameworks and libraries such as **Svelte**, Solid.js, and Ember.js. I am a seasoned expert in mobile app development using **Ionic** preferably.

I have a passion for user-friendly interface and its **performance**, and am often praised as a person who has a good eye for design. **Detail-oriented** and **responsible** work attitude brings high-level quality assurance, meaning that I am obsessed with writing code that is clean, performant and reliable.

Backend experience of mine includes **Node.js**, Express, **GraphQL**, MongoDB, PostgreSQL mostly as well as more traditional technologies like **Laravel** and MySQL.

For more information: https://louisyoung.vercel.app

SKILLS

- JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, TailwindCSS, Material UI, ChakraUI
- React/React Native, Vue.js, Svelte, Angular, Solid.js, Ember.js, Ionic, Electron.js, Redux, Mobx
- Inertia.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Quasar, Gatsby, Livewire
- Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Laravel, GraphQL/Apollo, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Git, Agile/scrum, Code review

EXPERIENCE



Zebedee, United States - *Front-end Web & Mobile Engineer*

SEPTEMBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

React | React Native | Flow | TypeScript | Redux | Jest | Mixpanel | iOS | Android

https://zebedee.io/app

https://zebedee.io/developers/dashboard

- Implemented complex UI elements and refactored whole CSS code using styled component and added core features such as bitcoin lightning invoice
- Reduced a fair amount of code lines and speeded up development cycle by replacing legacy Redux code with ReduxToolkit
- Migrated the whole React codebase from Flow to TypeScript to improve code reliability and legibility
- Owned product analytics feature using Mixpanel
- Wrote unit testing code using React testing library, Jest



Blocket AB, Sweden - Web & Mobile Engineer

FEBRUARY 2019 - JULY 2021

React | TypeScript | Next.js | Ionic | Capacitor | MaterialUI | GraphQL | Apollo | Node.js | Express | Prisma | PostgreSQL | Pusher

https://www.blocket.se

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=se.appcorn.Blocket

- Revamped UI with new figma design for both web and mobile screens and made reusable components with MaterialUI
- Solved device-dependent (iOS/Android) issues
- Optimized performance and improved UX by modularizing components, minimizing payload, code-splitting, lazy-loading, memoization/caching and image optimization
- API integration and state management using GraphQL Apollo
- Led mobile app development withlonic, React, Capacitor
- Wrote GraphQL schema, queries and mutations for early stage of backend
- Automated real-time notification with Pusher in Node.js backend



Pyszne Food Tech, Poland - Front-end Mobile Developer

DECEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Ionic | Cordova | React | TypeScript | Mobx | TailwindCSS | Socket.io

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yourdelivery.pyszne&hl=en&gl=US

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pyszne-pl/id1039818673

- Translated design team's UI/UX wireframes and mockups with TailwindCSS into well-organized and component-driven code
- Implemented core features while closely working with QA team and promptly reflecting needs of various clients and business objectives
- Rewrote all class-based components to functional components with TypeScript and custom hooks
- Utilized benefits of multi-store management by introducing Mobx
- Implemented real-time reporting of delivery status using Socket.io



FlorAcess, Netherlands - Full-stack Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Svelte | SvelteKit | ElasticSearch | Stripe | Node.js | Express | MongoDB

https://www.floraccess.com/

- Pixel-perfect implementation of the website according to the design provided by figma
- Integrated payment gateway with Stripe
- Worked on providing API endpoints with Node.js, MongoDB and mongoose
- Increased the search speed and performance by integrating ElasticSearch to the application



Michael Hill Jeweller, Australia - Front-end Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

Vue.js | Nuxt.js | PWA | Laravel | MySQL | CRM

https://www.michaelhill.com.au/

- Implemented SSR (server-side rendering) and SSG (static side generation) on SPA using Nuxt.js
- Created unique spaces for marketing ads within landing pages with custom CSS
- CRM dashboard for admin systems and visual representation of data using jQuery,
 Chart.is
- Utilized Google Maps APIs paired with data visualization tools
- Integrated Laravel APIs and assisted backend developer to optimize MySQL queries

EDUCATION



Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Bachelor of science (BS), Computer science

SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2015